the two steps in making a successful app
business are make
something worth using and then put it in
front of the people who would use it
if you have a plant and you don't know
what to do with it we solved that
problem
so what we did is we reached out to a
bunch of plant retailers hey we will
help your customers have a positive
outcome
with your product can you put in our
little qr code and now like
when these retailers ship out a new
plant every single one of them has this
little qr code in it it led to our first
000 users i'd say
[Music]
hey you're listening to the sub club
podcast a show dedicated to the best
practices for building
and growing subscription app businesses
we'll share insider secrets from the top
subscription apps on the app stores
let's get into the show welcome to the
sub club podcast
i'm your host david bernard and with me
as always jacob biden hello jacob
happy to be here you sound incredibly
happy that's great it's a friday david
the sun is shining they're they're
they're grilling a bunch of chickens in
my hometown
i got nothing to complain about it's
gonna be great our guest today is alex
ross founder and ceo at gregarious
makers of greg an app to help you grow
healthier and happier plants
prior to founding gregarious alex spent
four years as director of engineering at
tinder
alex also co-founded nplug a digital
signage company that was acquired
earlier this year
here welcome to the podcast alex
thank you guys good to see you thanks
david jacob hi
so i'm gonna try really hard this whole
podcast to not call you greg but i've
made that mistake
i was thinking like i get like annoying
company name questions sometimes i'm
like i'm sure you get
all way worse than me i'm considering
just legally adopting greg
as like a you know alias or something
yeah
you know that's a news cycle right there
a little bit of earned pr yeah
so i wanted to ask you um so obviously
you know director of engineering
at tinder that's i mean what a rocket
ship
that must have been quite a wild ride so
um
tell me a little bit about about how you
ended up at tinder and then
um you know if you do have any fun um
war stories from there that'd be great
to uh
to hear yeah definitely it was a rocket
ship
uh definitely some some war stories some
wins some losses
uh so i came across tinder um i was
looking to get into like a consumer
application um so i was interviewing
with
uber and twitter and then i came across
tinder on a angel list actually the head
of recruiting at the time reached out to
me and i kind of took it on a whim
uh to be honest i had not used the app
before
before even interviewing or anything
that's kind of a challenge for tinder is
like do you
how many of the teammates need to use
tinder because a lot of people are
married and in relationships and those
are great people to have on the team and
so it sounds kind of difficult or
complicated
um but basically i joined when it was
around 70 people
if i recall so it's a pretty small team
there was already a global
user base so it was one of the
scrappiest
global brands i think probably has ever
existed
because this was all right before tinder
or right around the time that tinder
launched its first
monetization efforts and so there wasn't
really awareness as to like
great there's this like large global
many millions of people are using this
thing
but is it gonna make money right that
was still an open question
um at the time that i joined um
so yeah basically i joined and it was
very um
it was definitely still a startup uh and
so there was not a lot of structure
and uh i think my manager changed on the
first day like
the person i was actually working with
desk changed and uh
but i had a great time and um basically
i ended up creating the growth team so i
became very focused on
um growing the international user base
and uh one of the coolest things that
that team did is
we decoupled tinder from facebook
and this was from facebook login because
like tinder came to came to fame by
having you know you
tap one button it imports your facebook
photos
it basically made online dating as easy
as it possibly can be because like you
push a button you're
in and then you're dating right and by
making it that simple
it made it so you felt less desperate by
using it i think it's like one of the
important
uh psychological you know dynamics
because if you feel like you
have to work to start using that
application then maybe it means that
like you
aren't having as much success dating in
the real world
and so by making it simpler it made it
less stigmatized more
cool right uh and so
when we decided to then allow people to
create accounts um
with a phone number that introduced all
this complexity around like well
are people going to want to do that work
um then they have to add
profile photos they have to type in
their name you have to introduce an
onboarding process
you have to worry about spam um so in
any case my team
led that decoupling of facebook and
tinder and this was like
pre-k analytica pre-gdpr so it was
definitely prescient it was like it was
a lot of good foresight
and it did lead it was a very successful
project um
and so that was kind of what i cut my
teeth on at tinder and then from there
i ended up creating the trust and safety
team so we then
kind of took on anti-spam which is a
major problem for any global
consumer especially a brand that you're
introducing people to each other like
you're introducing strangers to each
other mm-hmm
that is a spammer's dream there's so
much abuse on tinder so much of this
it was oh it was staggering yeah 24 7.
um
and so we ended up creating a team kind
of bottoms up this is a cool effort
because it wasn't like an executive said
like oh tinder needs to
needs to create this team but rather is
a collection of engineers that were very
motivated to solve this problem
and so we created a trust and safety
team again before
before gdpr like this was before the
world was really focused on
um privacy and and data security and
protecting
users very consciously it's interesting
because
now um you know i think even with like
clubhouse
recently had had issues here i think now
the expectation is you need trust and
safety from day one
yeah even five or six years ago wasn't
really the case it was kind of like well
just grow and then you'll solve it later
um so that was i would say early days
for even that concept of like a whole
dedicated team
this aspect yeah if you're meeting
people in public my god
like you need good safety features
yeah you really need to completely try
to protect people because there are
there's a rare selection of people that
are not great right
so yeah so then tell us a little bit
about the
the transition from being a tender to
founding a company because you've
founded companies before and plug
um and bennett um other large companies
before tinder but
yeah what what led you to uh to found
gregarious
yeah i actually saw jacob and i shared
an experience interning at cisco systems
is that right yeah
internal auditing um it was crazy i was
on a team that like
investigated other people for for like
uh you know abusing their corporate
cards and stuff like that so there'd be
like
interesting internally internally yeah
it was a very
they've had interns on that team
right now this is definitely the only
yeah wow
i was testing uh i was testing phones so
i'm actually not sure which one of those
is more boring
so that's it that's a tie that's a tie
for sure
um yeah so i got exposure cisco is
interesting for anybody who doesn't know
because you have to
drive between meetings right because the
campus is
the tasman campus yeah yeah yeah it's
talk about oh my gosh
culture um yeah so
the the process leading up to to
starting greg was very deliberate
um because i had done a startup before
and um that company had gone to success
successful outcome but it was a lot of
hard work it was honestly grueling
uh definitely like uh hardest challenge
in my life
and uh so i knew that i wanted to be
involved in starting a company and
building a culture from the ground up
again
um but i knew that i wanted to do it
differently and so basically there was a
lot of preparation thinking about
really that the main thing i was
thinking about is
what is the industry that i want to be
working in because i think that
startups often don't go the way you
expect
um but you can learn so much and so
i was really thinking like okay what do
i want to become an expert at
right like what do i want if it doesn't
work out in the way we expect what would
i
like to have learned four years five
years seven years worth of information
about
and uh i really kept coming back to
science
and i wanted to to kind of use my
engineering experience and pivot that
into
more real world like physical phenomena
right and like understanding how the
universe works
that's amazing and so that's really a
lot of the thesis of greg
is that we apply computer science and
software engineering
to this specific uh domain of how do
plants work
right and basically the the dots kind of
connect looking backwards but
it was a process of discovery of like
what's an area that's
emerging and like kind of changing like
where is there an opportunity right
because i think it's helpful to position
yourself at a place where
either you can cause change or this
change already happening and uh
right now like a lot of people know
there's climate change um
and there's also a lot of rapid things
happening in plant science world um
specifically around like crispr and
plant genetics and stuff like that
really at the deep end of it which we
can get into it's like way
deep but uh but basically
this was before the pandemics we were
actually looking into plants before
covid and already there was like the
rate of people bringing plants into
their homes was growing by
50 to 100 per year and
we wanted to validate wow wait wait
really yeah that seems like that seems
like a thing that would be fairly stable
like uh is it is it is it a is it a
generational trend like millennials
or younger folks being i have a lot of
people on twitter i follow that seem
very interested in plants
more than i have ever been there's a
couple converging trends yeah
i think a part of it it's associated to
like the mental wellness movement
so it's kind of this trend line follows
one that's very similar to like
meditation
and yoga just five years later so i
think it's a very it's a lot of adjacent
interests there
but then there's also an aesthetic
component to plants where like people
are kind of decorating their spaces and
they're getting more like trendy and in
how they
you know how they even people who are
dating like you want to have like
a space that you invite someone into and
it's very nurturing right
um so yeah there was definitely a
generational kind of tailwind already
happening
and then kovid just like cranked that up
right because then
everybody's on zoom and you look in the
background and some people have plants
and you're like oh that looks kind of
nice like i'd like that
i have this i have i still have this
like barren white wall back here that it
was all embarrassing
yeah i need that's why i was excited i i
installed greg today and i was
disappointed i couldn't buy the plants
in the app yet so we'll have to talk
about that
it's coming that is coming that is the
segment yeah
definitely um yeah so we kind of saw an
opportunity and we did some due
diligence some interesting things i
think to identify
like is there a revenue opportunity and
my favorite stat that i like to share
that blew my mind when i learned it
is home depot is a publicly traded
company so you can look up their you
know
annual statements and you can see how
are they making money
and if you look up their statements
you'll see that they make more money
on indoor garden than on any other
product segment
it's like home depot sells lumber paint
appliances
uh all these other things that's like
that's like actual revenues
is that also a margin because i would
imagine these are high margin items as
well
i would guess yeah yeah depending on
where you're following them but yeah
they're they're pretty high margin um
and no i we only looked at revenue but
they make
like last night like 11 billion dollars
per year in revenue
um which is uh and they're like that's
one
store right that's one sport yeah yeah
and there's like every town has four of
these
right exactly yeah and home depot is
like 10 or 15 percent of the plant
retail market probably it's hard to
estimate that okay yeah
so it's like rough like 100 billion
dollar a year kind of thing in the us
yeah and other estimates pin like that's
the size of in-app subscriptions for
anybody who's curious like roughly
like in that ballpark yeah yeah exactly
like apple's app store subscription
oh yeah sorry app store it's not even
subscriptions i think that's the app
store broadly yeah
that so we so we combined the plant
tam with then the app store growth in
subscription revenue
and there's our business model there you
go did you did you
i mean yeah you mentioned like wanting
to get into something physical into
something science related did you have
like a passion for plants or was this
something that
is like deep in you or or was it more
like me in an app subscriptions which
was like well this looks like a good
thing i could work on and i actually
care about it and know a little bit
about it right so
how did it uh how did you go like yeah
this is what i want to do
that's a great question it was like 75
percent the latter
same as you where it was kind of i got
exposed to it because i started getting
plants and i realized i did like them
but there was no brand to guide me and
there was definitely no science to help
me keep them alive right
um but i i grew up in the mountains and
so like i i my family
we i lived in mammoth lakes california
for any of the listeners
and so i you know i went on like a solo
backpacking trip
like shortly before starting all this
and kind of communed with like
being in nature with more people around
me and maybe that put me in touch with
the plants a little bit more
but it was mostly uh kind of identifying
this is a realm of science i'd like to
work in because plants are mostly
physics based this is something a lot of
people don't don't realize
but because they're stationary you can
almost view them as like
like a civil engineer would a bridge um
so there's not so you kind of really
think about like the water physics the
light physics and so they're a really
great vehicle
for learning um just physics generally
and also how like the sun and
earth orbit matters to that plant in
that location
there's so much science there that we
learned that there's a depth that was
we were very interested in diving deeper
into yeah not to mention
not to mention biology right
right yeah it's a big part of it yeah
biology is difficult though right like
if you're like an engineer who's trying
to approach it
right yeah it's messy you know exactly
yeah yeah but if you think about it as a
closed system right
like yeah you have it's potted it's
planted you know uh
lumens in you know water in you know
nutrients in
yeah you can uh yeah you can you can
make some
approximations right as we like to say
the closed system is is really
important i can uh so so what greg does
is greg
predicts when a given plant is going to
need to be watered
that's like the super simple like
simplified functionality it's one of the
main things you need to know
um and the way we figured that out
talking about closed systems is kind of
a fun fact
you can very accurately measure the
amount of water that a plant loses
by weighing it on one day and then
weighing it
the next day and the change in weight is
the
water lost in grams and it turns out so
what we did is we did that for like 700
plants for like six months
and we then graphed what it was the
grams of water lost per plant per day
and you get this beautiful pattern um
it's like
this isn't random like this is a very
clear like almost a heartbeat of a plant
um which is a great fit for like machine
learning right
yeah so so so how did how did you pull
this off like practically did you have
like a
big garage or warehouse or something
like that that's that's
more work than i usually do for software
so
me what that process was i definitely
did so at one point i had like 150
plants and they all had uh
plastic uh little pots and i had like
labels i named them like
a one through nine and then c one
through whatever because i had to keep
track of it right it's all in our
postgres database and uh
but that didn't scale and so like me and
my co-founders we were all measuring
every day
every single day hundreds of plants that
didn't scale so then we went on
craigslist
and we started saying like hey we're
looking for people to weigh their plants
every day twice per day for a couple
months
and we had hundreds of responses like
people people care about their plants
and they thought that it was cool to be
doing like
citizen science right and so we ended up
with people in berlin and then
you know sydney and all right because
this has to be local right
yeah and actually it needs to be in like
southern hemisphere versus northern
hemisphere because the
location of like the sun and solar
radiation affects it
yeah so we needed a global distribution
for sure
this is like way off topic for um for
subscription apps but
if you if you squint it's there are a
lot of similar problems in understanding
user patterns and user life cycle and
like there's so many
hard to understand variables um
yeah but one thing i'm curious about on
the plant science front like how much
does like humidity and other things play
into that so if you
if you have you know 40 humidity one day
and 60 the next does that actually
impact things
no humidity we don't really need to
model humidity very much um it's
actually
there's a couple of misconceptions um
you don't really need to worry about
misting or humidity
and you don't need to worry about
fertilizing like all that is overdone
um for the most part like there's some
cases where it matters
but um i'd say for like 99 out of 100
plant
types that you're likely to own doesn't
matter and even more
people don't realize that the humidity
reading that we see in the weather
is what's called relative humidity and
it
it's not actually like a super
scientific way to measure like
how the water in the air relates to a
plant you need to look at absolute
humidity
the whole totally different calculation
there's like basically relativity
changes according to the temperature and
so
right yeah humidity you can almost to be
honest like uh
ignore except for a couple of plants
that like really evolved to be in like
you can picture like
uh you know in england like a united
kingdom like bog
right whereas there's so much water like
okay well those
like some ferns like are from like the
pacific northwest like washington area
where it's like constant rainforest
those types of plants yeah you're gonna
have a hard time if you're not um
in a very humid environment but the vast
majority of you buy don't have to worry
about it
i have i have more questions on plant
physics but i think uh
i think i will let i will i will have to
like save my curiosity have to do the uh
we'll have to jump on your podcast and
uh talk
talk plans just invite if you need two
two newbies on there just ask questions
we'll be there
so from um from all of this you you've
started to allude to it a bit
but one of the things i was really
impressed talking to you a couple of
months ago
um was just how ambitious your plans are
with greg so you're kicking it off with
a consumer subscription app
um but tell me a little bit about like
where you want to go from there
yeah definitely that's a part of like
going back to like
how we started it why we started it um i
i have seen or like i've worked at
companies and like not naming names
that are very very revenue focused
like just purely prime directive is we
just need to make coin
and as much of it as possible right and
then the question is well if you get
there then what do you do
because if you do accumulate a lot of
revenue and a lot of influence
you kind of inherit a social
responsibility right because like you're
accumulating all these resources if
you're like a facebook or an instagram
i think there's like general consensus
like you kind of need to think about the
impact that you have because you're
too big to not think about it right and
so with greg
like we really thought about if we
managed to navigate
this very challenging process of getting
to scale
well then what right and
our goal what's really interesting that
people don't realize is that
plants in our homes are just
plants that were taken from various
places in the world and put in our homes
right
like there there's no such thing as a
house plant it's actually just like a
giant
jungle tree that somebody took a cutting
from and then transported it to
england and then ended up the united
states right
so the physical principles that govern
being able to predict
how to keep those plants alive is are
the same as the physical principles
required to predict how to keep like
crops
alive right um like plants that are
grown for our food system of which
they're like
billions right and those plants like it
turns out plants are really like an
infrastructure piece
of our planet right like plants are our
life support system
on spaceship earth and it's kind of
interesting it's the it's the first
stage of catalyzing
the sun's resources right like that's
exactly it and
a lot of people don't realize this that
basically all of life
gets its energy from the sun like that
is the input of all of energy into
what we know as life as you know maybe
there's more on other planets that works
differently but as far as we know all of
life depends on solar energy
yeah uh alex you're leaving out some
very
very sensitive uh bacteria that live by
vents
okay i love it i love that you know this
jacob
this makes i'm disappointed myself i
can't think of what they're called
they're extremophiles some kind of yeah
it's all it's all uh
it's all discovery documentaries there's
a vanishingly small
number of uh like living things that uh
thrive on geothermal energy from the
earth's core right but that's like less
than like one percent as far as i know
yeah
um what people don't realize as an
example is that
like plants a lot of people think that
plants are just taking things out of the
ground like sucking nutrients out
sucking water out
they're actually also putting things
back into the ground at all times
and so plants like for example they
photosynthesize so they take energy from
the sun
and they are the only thing on the
planet that takes energy from the sun
and then converts it into energy that
all other life can use and it's not only
insects and birds and
mammals like us but plants are also
depositing
sugar into the soil so it's a
bi-directional flow
and that sugar feeds the bacteria is
that an active process while they're
alive is it or is it during
decomposition
no that is an active process like plants
are actively um depositing sugar
into the soil and that that those sugars
feed the bacteria and fungi
and those bacteria and fungi are
responsible for
breaking down the inorganic nutrients
like nitrogen
into a a format that plants can absorb
because plants can't just like suck
nitrogen out they depend on
those organic you know facilitators
and so it's a very symbiotic
relationship and there's growing
awareness now that like having a
quote-unquote living soil is crucial
for our planet and i'll tell you like an
example of how
how much awareness there is around this
um during my due diligence for greg
i went to a plant genetics conference
this is like
right for any engineers in the call like
imagine like aws re invent
except it's a geneticist right and so
they're like presenting like how they
run their projects and it's a really
cool parallel
world but half of this conference was
dedicated to
soil like microbiomes because that's how
important it is it's like truly like a
resource it's an infrastructure for our
spaceship earth
right that's amazing so
so one of the things you and i talked
about was not just
you know consumer subscription to then
like funding
science which is kind of what you were
talking about now but then also the
potential to
take this from from b to c to b to b so
like
you have um nurseries who have to manage
the plants before the people buy them
you have
office buildings that have thousands of
plants you have
you know commercial facilities like
there's you know plants existed
on so many different layers of our of
of of use um
so tell me a little bit about kind of
the the long and short term plans
of potentially transitioning or not
transitioning but but kind of building
on top of what you've done for consumers
to then expand into more b2b um
uh use cases yeah definitely some other
examples um
people don't realize that cities have to
like municipalities have to maintain
their plant inventories right like there
are people who manage the inventory of
plants they don't just
exist you know or there are
small businesses uh there are people in
most towns that grow food for their
farmers markets for example
um and so those are like smaller scale
farmers and then there's large-scale
farmers right
and there's a real dearth of like
talented software teams writing
applications for any of those parties
that's really the long-term opportunity
to be spotted if we can pull together
a talented team to make products for
those people that's a long-term
opportunity
and my my thesis on this um
which i think we're aligned on is that
uh
like delightful simple consumer user
interfaces
like simple software is appreciated by
everybody right like enterprises don't
want to use
complicated interfaces there's taste now
in software right
in all levels of employment i think it's
it's a bit of
like our my generation aging into the
the
enterprise buying world and um also just
like people
have enough software experiences in our
lives they've learned to discern like oh
this is good and oh this is bad
um and i think there's yeah i think it's
really i mean we
i've i've done it a ton in making
revenue account i came from the computer
subscription world i learned a ton of
lessons about onboarding and
and and and creating delightful
experiences and like you know
playing playing against and into
people's like
in you know habits and things like this
that you carry into the
enterprise world or b2b world and it can
really supercharge software and it's
probably what we're going to see
hey i i i i i think
i think there's still there's always
this like technical
leap or not technical in the sense of
computers but technical in the sense of
processes and and what not when you leap
from consumer to
to selling to businesses but as you said
you bring those teams together you you
build your data set you learn more about
right the act of growing plants then you
know someday you you
you can you can launch into those spaces
right and there are some some famous
examples of this
i definitely see it with revenue cat
because like you compare the ui to
a sas that was created 10 years ago and
it's just more delightful right it's
like simple and i know to use and i'm
not like getting a headache while i'm on
it
it's nice right compared to this it's
very nice of you to say
yeah i'm biased um but but like some
examples like stripe
became famous right because like they
had a good developer
which is almost a consumer like like uh
consumer
say my mindset right just like make it
easy make it simple make the
make the shortest possible path to value
right exactly
yeah it's great slack would be another
example right where's almost a consumer
level application that just took off
like wildfire because
individuals liked it right and then they
added enterprise grid
whatever they have now to sell it to to
walmart
but nothing else they didn't need that
to begin with yeah right
yeah so it's just it's really cool that
there's there's just such a direct
path from selling to consumers right now
and then selling to municipalities who
are managing their plants in a few years
and then selling to
you know the companies who have to
manage this at scale
and then selling to farmers it's that's
really cool
um one of one of the things
that again that you and i talked about
you and i talked for like two hours
a couple months ago and so there's
there's so much that i would i would
have loved to have recorded that and
released it as a podcast but uh thanks
david
glad i can glad i can contribute
one of the one of the fascinating things
that you talked about was kind of your
view on marketing
and so i'd love for you to talk about
that more broadly but then
specifically what you're doing with
nurseries
is just such incredibly smart marketing
like
i mean it let me say change it for a
minute
so it's just so obvious talking to you
that you're not the average like app
founder
you know like none of my apps have had
even
even like one 100th of the
due diligence and like market
understands
i've never i've never bought something
like i've never had a physical
warehouse of plants um
and so it's just it's just so clear that
you you think about things in a way that
that most you know app people don't
most software people don't most even
founders don't
um and and so i i think you know we've
talked about this on the podcast before
this is just so many apps are trapped in
this
you know we just we have to advertise on
facebook to grow we have to do this
and like that playbook of just you know
dump a money
bunch of money in ads i think leaves so
much on the table and so
i just love that you're you're going to
do that and then we've talked about that
um you know you're gonna do paid
marketing and and maybe you have already
started experimenting with it but
uh but yeah so tell me about what you're
doing with nurseries and then just kind
of
you know some of your thoughts on on
marketing and virality and stuff
yeah definitely i think broadly like
what i would i think
i'm definitely aligned with that where
uh your broader point is that like
building an app is half technical
and ui design and getting the product
really really really right right
but the other half that people are often
uncomfortable about
is needing to get it in front of the
right people
right and so in my mind the way i break
this down is the two steps like i have a
theory that like the two steps in making
a successful app business are
make something worth using and then
put it in front of the people who would
use it right and it's like remarkably
hard to do either one of those
but um once we had uh the beginning
signs
of retention so we got our first like i
don't know 5
000 users by like posting on facebook
and on reddit and like that kind of
stuff
then we started thinking about um
what is like the most optimal time for
people to be introduced to grade
and what we came up with is well
we solved the problem of uh if you have
a plant
and you don't know what to do with it
how to keep it alive we solve that
problem
and so the most natural moment would be
when you get a new plan
right because it's like that's the
moment you're like oh crap i have this
thing how do i how do i keep it alive
and uh so what we did is we reached out
to a bunch of
uh plant retailers like online in person
brick and mortar
all over the place and we basically said
like hey we will
help your customers have a positive
outcome with your product
right and so let's do this trade where
like we will give them
um at this point we had a subscription
tier and so we said we'll give them free
subscription tier for n number of months
the first day was six and now it's three
um and in return can you put in our
little
qr code flyer like nicely designed four
inches by four inches
recycled paper card that has a qr code
it takes you to download greg
right and so we did that and now like
when these retailers
ship out a new plant every single one of
them has this little qr code in it
and it's almost like a digital companion
to your unboxing experience right and so
that was definitely like
a very natural fit and it it led to our
first um
probably like 10 or 20 000 15 000 users
i'd say
so can i ask like um did you do that
yourself did you have somebody on your
team because like yeah i'm i'm in the
camp that that's outside my experience i
don't like calling the pizza person like
i
you know i i don't know how to do that
so how did you how did you delegate that
and
and and find the resources and a small
team to pull that off
definitely um so i i'd say i provided
the oomph
behind it but then i have a good friend
who i've worked with in the past named
colin
who does like growth marketing stuff and
that's his comfort zone
right and so i definitely did reach out
to
a bunch of the biggest partners in the
beginning
um because the thing is that like with
early stage stuff founder-led
sales can be great right like you don't
always need it
it's better if you don't need it to be
frank um but
we were so early and we had no partners
at all that i was like i have this is
crucial for us like we need to have
a better source of user acquisition
that's like our next major challenge to
solve
and so i did reach out to them and then
colin kind of like took over and scaled
that
right because like ultimately like i
needed to be writing code and stuff
um and so that now he owns that
relationship and he's been able to
to keep that going further um yeah
just one of these unique channels that
um
you know i don't know you can as a b2c
app founder i think david's point's
exactly on i think we've
a lot of us have settled into this world
where there's one or two channels to
like get growth and that's
paid marketing there's a lot of good um
growth resources out there
um yeah there's a lot of good
growth books i've read moving into the
b2b world that say there's like seven
channels or whatever there's only
so many like ways to get and then and
and in b2c we tend to be like well yeah
there's these two
essentially but it's not really true
like you you can try stuff and
i guess the trick is finding stuff that
two things
one is approachable like that's why i
asked about you
how did you make it happen well you were
able to start it off and then you had
somebody to work with you to to
to bring it to scale but then the other
thing is it has to move the needle
right and so you and so you have to
figure out and like for a price that's
reasonable right and that sometimes is
hard to find as well because
i think with this you have this adjacent
high velocity market of users you have a
place
your users are going every day which
isn't maybe always the case for all apps
right it's hard to find there's no
meditation store that people are going
to every day right
but i thought there you go that's your
that's your
advantage you know i thought about
parallels like i wonder if like
fitness apps have tried partnering with
gyms um
yeah i'm thinking like fitbot i'm sure
the gyms wouldn't uh be as eager
maybe right well yeah i mean possibly
i'm just thinking like
if if like there's also like some
there's also this like benefit right
from the for the
plan right yeah yeah yeah but i would
just just like theorycraft like i'm
thinking if there's an app that helps
you
track your workouts like i use football
i'm a user um
it's a great app and uh and it's a
complete compliment to the gym like i
can't
do gym without i can't do fitbit without
gym i don't really do gym without fit
bod
so i there might be a thing there or
like with meditation i'd be curious
if uh like yoga studios because here's
the thing is find that adjacencies right
yeah yeah and so here's the thing about
a mobile app business that i have found
is that one of our strengths
is that we're building an audience right
like mobile apps only really work with
retention
and so you're like building up this
audience of people that are committed to
your app and your brand over time
and these smaller businesses are looking
for ways to get
audiences right and so in the scale of a
mobile app is such that
you might actually be able to accumulate
an audience that is valuable to those
small businesses
that can be a part of that trade and so
we've actually talked about that with
our partners
we basically say like well you're
referring users to us
we can refer users back to you and our
scale is large enough that it could
actually be a meaningful number
um so i think you can kind of get it's
definitely a b2b strategy where it's
like
i'm thinking of the strategic value i
can provide to my partners in return for
them providing value to us
which might be why it's less common in
the in the b2c like mobile app world
right
yeah any other um experiments that
you've done or kind of things that
you're working on in the in the
marketing realm that you've
seen fail or things that are being
successful right now
we really want to tap peer-to-peer
referrals
and that has not been easy and so that
that is one that like have you seen have
you seen the new store kit 2 stuff
uh yeah they this is i don't know when
this is gonna go
out but they they dropped in in in the
wwdc this
this this week they announced there's a
new api that's going to make that kind
of possible now
we'll be able to you'll be able to like
extend somebody else's subscription
based on some sort of like action i
think i i don't know if
they they made it as like um uh for
extending
for like a support use case so there
might be okay maybe apple's like no we
didn't want you to use it for
incentivized referrals but it could
totally make incentivized referrals work
in like a
really smooth way sorry on derail but uh
it's kind of a change yeah well it's
probably useful to listeners um
we have definitely hacked around
incentivized invites using
promotionals i will say revenue cat has
been helpful
oh so and and so you guys are you guys
are pushing folks but they have to go
through like this like
uh user driven process right they do
yeah which is
friction it's friction it's been fine
but it's not quite as productive as we'd
like so that one
i have a lot of users that get confused
about the process i would imagine
yeah and it's like a deep linky thing so
it's like not super transparent
um the thing that's worked better the
one i'm most excited about
is i love this one um we uh
created uh user generated content loops
so basically people there are certain
things you can do in our app that like
publish web pages on the web um
and so for us very specifically it's
that people
like greg uh we don't have a database of
like every plant in the world
yet right there's like 400 000 it's
really complicated and like
that's actually one of our core ips is
developing that database
and the only way we can do it is if we
allow users to contribute to it
right um we need to be like a crowd
source like model and we get really good
at
curation so people can create
new species in greg and then we curate
that and then we publish that page
on the web and then it starts showing up
in google search traffic for other
people searching for information about
that species right
and so i love the theory of this and
like check back in in a year to see how
it turns out but i love it
because it's like okay a user publishes
a web page
which then more users find our app
through so then they join the app and
then they publish more web pages
and then so more users find the app and
then they publish more web pages right
and so it's like a very like
positive reinforcement loop and i think
those types of recursive
positive reinforcing user growth loops
can lead to very
healthy uh growth curves right yeah i
mean that's the
the the challenge of these apps you said
it with retention is the big thing i
think
you you're you're you've got some
tailwinds with keeping a plant alive
plants live a long time therefore
hopefully your app gets used a long time
but then
um finding these things that can take
what is inherently like a decaying
process which is people leaving your app
and turning it into something more
stable which is how you build this like
yeah
long-term business and then you know
from your case like use this as a
platform to move into other segments
and whatnot but but but moving away
uh from this like get them in monetize
them let them go right model which like
it seems just like the whole world's
pointing us against right with with the
way that ad tracking is getting less
easy to do and all this stuff
um so i was gonna say seo that's one of
the seven
channels right so you've hit at least
three
you do end up dependent on on google uh
and
right and then something can change in a
moment's notice right but like i've been
i've been watching seo for a while and i
think that generally as long as you're
not doing
shady things you don't have to worry
that much right
make make content that people click on
and find useful it will work right like
but when i did our blogs for revenue cat
initially the ones that got really good
traffic for us kind of got us off the
ground like i didn't i didn't think like
i thought a little bit like uh what are
people gonna google whatever but no it's
just like i'll just make
posts that people will read and spend
time on and share and like
that's all it took and you'll find the
post that
some of the posts that i did that were
intentionally like i'm trying to be like
seo smart didn't do that well the ones
where they were just really good posts
and like contained a lot of really good
content and get referenced a lot those
are the ones that still generate traffic
for us so like
um which is nice because you don't have
to be like an seo
master anymore you can kind of just make
good stuff and do the smart things yeah
yeah i was going to ask you so have you
i think we talked about this but have
you
have you done some paid marketing and
how's that gone for you
yeah definitely we did use paid
marketing to like uh
scale up uh by like a 2x factor so that
add a little bit of extra
and um so we've been running on
instagram and facebook um and it's been
pretty productive to the point where
it's almost
net spend zero um so like we spend a
dollar in advertising and then we make a
dollar in revenue
um we're still very early and so we
haven't have enough months like
the the pain point is if you do a trial
it's actually a much longer
uh payback period or like what finance
people would call afloat than a lot of
people expect because
let's say you have we're generous we
have a 30-day trial which is like a bit
much for a mobile app but we do it
and so 30 days and then the user
subscribes um and then you get paid and
then apple
will pay you a month later right so you
actually end up with like up to a 90-day
float
um and so that's not as tight as i would
like hope for
but it's better than nothing and i think
that's the key is that like
because we're a revenue generating app
we're able to do the ad spend in like a
reasonable way
i think if that weren't the case it'd be
very difficult
yeah and at some point i mean
with with your other strategies of
referrals of seo of
building a base of users that then you
can
get more and more partners you know so
so if you went to home depot and said we
have
10 million active users then that's a
much more attractive proposition to them
um so at some point you know spending at
a loss might actually make sense
but it's amazing that the subscription
um model enables you to
even spend break even but keep that
flywheel going which is it's
that's incredible and i think the
netspend break even that creates an
interesting exercise because then it's
like
it becomes we get into like financing
but like if you fundraise
that's then a good reason to fundraise
because then if you have more capital
you can put that capital
to work um because if you know you'll
make if you have a dollar now
you'll have a dollar again in 90 days as
long as you can
carry that float well then at the end of
90 days you have a dollar
and a user right yeah which is like has
has value right like you've increased
the value of
your user base has adult you know dollar
per user active value essentially in the
venture market or however you value it
right so um
it does make sense so yeah i i want i
want to ask like
so you you guys it seems like your app's
pretty developed for how long you've
been working on it a year in change
right
um and you mentioned you mentioned this
um
like finding iterating to like a
retention goal like how did that go did
you start with just like
the basic function like the most basic
thing and then add stuff until you got
and what what i guess specifically like
what metric were you looking at to say
okay retention is good now yeah it's a
great question
so we we did start with the most basic
core functionality and i think one of
the things we did that i would do again
is we just solved our own problem so
like i so we started the beginning of
covid so like new york where i live
locked down basically the day almost the
day that i left tinder
right and so and so i remember i'll
never forget
things were shutting down so i ran to
the nursery nearby
plant nursery and i bought like 30 30
plants because i was like i need to have
the problem
in order to be deeply motivated to solve
it right because like if you actually
have like over 10 plants keeping track
of them kind of sucks a little bit it's
hard
um and so i knew that i needed the
problem and that motivated us and our
whole team really
we basically just wrote like a prototype
app to solve our own problem
um and once it was working for us is
when we started
bringing like beta users in we did like
a test flight
version for a month brought in like
maybe a thousand or i think it was two
thousand beta users total and they're
in like august 2020 and uh how did you
get that list for the beta
just facebook and it was mostly facebook
it was mostly facebook like groups and
stuff like that
um yeah um and
they posted on reddit reddit is hard um
but uh we did a little bit of that
ripoff middlemen made easy that's my
favorite we posted i posted red it was
where we launched too and i have this
this favorite hater quote that i have
like screenshotted on my desktop that
i'll hold on to
until we ipo yeah the hater quotes are
something people should be prepared for
i think yeah but
let's see so we solved the here's the
key is that we we specifically
for our app we wanted to solve the
retention piece first
and so we chose the behavior in the app
that would be associated with retention
because
the way that i personally think about
retention is that what
what happens is you have a trigger so a
person needs an external trigger to
think about opening your app
right so it could be a feeling that they
have like tinder it's a feeling i'm
bored or i'm lonely
and i want to see people and that's an
external trigger that causes a person to
think about your app
then you need value to for them to
actually open your app right like okay i
have this trigger in this app can
address that trigger so for us we didn't
have like
an emotion but we did have uh
the need for reminders and so basically
we
uh leverage push notifications very
heavily our whole app is like
a water reminder app right now that's
like the core value
and so we built that specific
functionality water reminders before
anything else because we wanted to
validate
is that a sticky behavior is that
something that people will actually
want to do and use over like six months
right
and because we knew we wanted to get six
months of data we had to build it first
right because you have to really think
about how long it's going to take to get
that validation
and we were bootstrapped and so we knew
that like well we can't bootstrap for
forever
right and so we we needed to front load
the questions that we knew investors
would be asking
when we went out to fundraise so
speaking of which
you just raised 5.4 million dollars
seed round um
tell us about the the process it sounds
like you were you know having been a
tinder
and been in silicon valley in the
industry
um that was your goal you didn't come
into it thinking you were going to
bootstrap this forever
and you were specifically kind of
building up some of those retention
numbers and other things that you knew
investors would ask for
um so how so how did fundraising go
having kind of iterated into that
direction
uh it's definitely hard as hell um i
don't know like
you don't ever say that it's not um but
it wasn't it wasn't like excruciating um
i think recruiting is actually probably
a little bit more difficult especially
right now there's a lot of a lot of
movement in the in the
why people are working how they want to
work it's easier it's easier to write a
check than it is to take a job i think
you know
like to give in somebody to do you can
write multiple checks
right yeah it's not like it's not your
everyday
you know exactly yeah so um
let's see we actually to go back to your
first point
we weren't um completely we hadn't
decided that we were definitely going to
raise vc capital
so there was like like we did work
through that as a team and we ended up
deciding
very specifically that our mission is
one that we believe
would benefit from us being good at
raising capital because we think that if
we can bring capital
and talent to this industry in this
problem domain
um that's a good thing and then even
from a life perspective like we wanted
we want to move quick we want to like be
able to grow we want to be able to like
build delightful things for lots of
people
um and so that was that was the main
motivation behind the vc capital i think
it's a big trade-off um so we definitely
did not take it lightly and we did
deeply
it closes off a lot of paths right it
kind of puts you kind of really narrows
what your future i mean
kind of shoots you on a trajectory to
something potentially much much bigger
but it really kind of like brings down
your your options a lot
it does yeah i think you start to think
about like am i okay
with needing to focus on eventually
providing an exit
to these people who trusted with their
capital right
yeah and i think maybe something people
don't think about is like the ceo
or whoever is fundraising like you you
build a relationship with your your vc
partners right like
i consider them like life journey
partners at this point
and so it's not that like it's
definitely not an adversarial
relationship it's more like i have a
true responsibility to these people
because we had a clear like this is
their agreement it's like capital and
then
they have obligation to their investors
too and so
you know i'm aligned with that and i
think you're right you have to think
about like
is that is that aligned with my vision
for this this journey right
and then speaking of of an exit um
you shared with me you have a very
unique approach
to employee equity i'm actually curious
to hear
jacob's take on this um having gone
through the whole thing
uh himself but yeah tell us about your
equity structure
yeah we we definitely are uh
experimenting and trying something
different and i think there's pros and
cons and investors love
that by the way sure those were easy
conversations
surprisingly most investors were were
okay with it
um i definitely had a couple that were
concerned about um the implications in
the medium term
but here i'll get to what it is so yeah
tell me what it is yeah okay so
basically like
we um wanted to distribute as much of
the financial ownership of the company
across as many of the early teammates
as we could um and the reason for this
like the real thought that i had
that whether or not other people think
about this kind of thing i would i would
encourage people to ask
this which is um if i have an exit
how big of an exit would i really want
to feel very fortunate about
right and like really think about like
how much money do i actually
need right because i think that there's
a lot of people who get caught up with
like
i want a billion dollars right like i
want like 100 million dollars and
i've been fortunate enough like we
pointed out earlier my first company was
required for like
a fine amount and then tinder totally
exploded i didn't own as much of it but
it was still a positive outcome
and i can say that like it didn't change
anything and i know it's a very cliched
thing to say but i think it's a
productive exercise that if anybody was
founding a company i would recommend
asking
at what point am i again feeling
fortunate about the outcome right
and then what we really thought about is
our ability to recruit a great team
and basically the decision that we made
is that um
there's really two aspects to equity uh
and i'd be curious again jacob's take on
this there's
there's compensation for risk so early
teammates take more risk
quote unquote right and so that that's a
typical like reason for
uh founders taking a large opportunity
costs risk mostly right but yeah
opportunity costs and risk and then the
other dimension that i think about
is effort where uh early stage companies
are hard for everybody who's involved
and my prior experience pointed towards
like
the first 20 people who joined the
company or at least definitely 10 or 15
all worked uh pretty much as hard and
definitely at least not like
10 it's possible we're 10 times harder
right and so
with less and with less glory to be
honest right like less glory they don't
they don't they don't get all the likes
on
follows on twitter or whatever right try
to distribute it but yeah
it's it's it's it's a grindy place to be
for sure
not getting the glory is like a it's
definitely a double-edged sword because
i think that that glory is also a
responsibility right but right um
yeah and so basically we decided to try
this approach where we wanted to
do this exercise of distributing that
equity as equally as possible
and so we set up a mathematical curve
where
whenever i make an offer i just look at
this math equation of like
what is the amount of equity this next
person gets right
um and and so and we did that and
basically projected out like okay each
person gets to like like if we reached a
billion dollar company
each teammate should have an outcome of
something like 10 million dollars or
more
right like something something above
that number and it was really important
to map
that out because otherwise it can go
sideways
and yeah and so basically that was our
exercise and we basically said like okay
can we
can we turn that around a little bit and
um the
side effect that i like so again we're
early in this like we're we're a
eight person team growing to 15 and it
may turn out to be complicated and again
we check in in a year
but what i like about it is that it did
enable a completely transparent cap
table right and that's nice because like
i don't think it's like maybe required
but i do
like being able to show people like this
is who owns this company
with you right yeah exactly
yeah so that's a positive side effect um
but there's definitely
it's complicated yeah well so david
my take is actually we do something very
similar yeah
also like so interestingly and and
inside inside baseball i think
um it it's it's we we did um
something similar no we weren't as
scientific with it for the first like
we had like a rough rule but it was like
the same like each number
like the the number like decrease like
with this back off i found it a very
it's a very hard problem to reason about
because you
you don't want to think about this you
want the 100th employee to have some
skin in the game
exactly right but you you need to
balance that with like hey like come
join this company that you've never
heard of and like probably has like
worst benefits and
you know who knows it's going to be it's
going to be a mess right and so like
finding that balance is really hard
um and and you know i'm looking at where
we're at 30 people now
and the complexity definitely grows and
then i think also
you start thinking about like recruiting
leverage and like what you know what
how much equity do i need to offer to be
able to like recruit these different
types of roles and things like that
and your systems get more complex but um
but
but it's still did you guys did you do
something special special on founder
equity to create like more
more room on the cap table or did you
how many co-founders do you have
uh that's such a blurry line i don't
know if this is just me but i
never know like well is that the fourth
person like
no i guess that's true i mean uh yeah i
guess that's a
maybe that's a it's a yc thing is where
they're like very clear
like who are the co-founders and who are
not right
but yeah i i agree it's probably mostly
a a label
i feel like we have six co-founders um
realistically
there were two of us that were like
thinking about this you know like that's
not true there are three of us that were
thinking about this like two years ago
um so we i i call them co-founders and
so
we're all on this same plan so like we
have this graph where like i am the
first black
yeah yeah yeah it's truly distributed
like as much as possible and so the
hardest
this plan is definitely hardest on the
first three people
and it requires incredible cultural
buy-in to that
because it means that outcome like i i
definitely worked on this for a lot
longer than like the people who were
joining today
right and like it was stressful and hard
but here's here's my
my my personal take and is that
i actually think the risk of doing
startups and i feel like yc may agree
with this
the risk of doing startups is like so
much lower than most people realize
for people who have the fortune of
having a safety net
right like if you're if you have a
family and you don't have savings then
like of course that is
that is a risky proposition but for
people who are relatively early or
mid-stage in their careers
and they have savings and they're not
actually going to end up in a really
dangerous spot
then i think that startups are almost
always a net positive
if you really apply yourself because the
amount that you learn and grow
by solving that many problems uh only
accelerates your career
right and so going back to the risk
versus
there's also opportunity cost and then
there's effort i personally discount the
risk
for people who are fortunate enough to
have that safe space
i discount that risk almost to zero
because i think that
it's just such a even this time around
for me my second startup i have learned
so much and it's been such a good life
experience that even if it didn't work
out tomorrow
net win for sure yeah
so part of the reason i brought it up
was that i
when i joined i told dick of this when i
joined revenue this is way inside
baseball i don't know why we're getting
this uh
open and opening up on the podcast but
when i joined revenue cat
i thought more along the lines of you
alex like i thought well why
is jacob getting so much more of the
company and then and
revenue caps uh like the first 10
employees and then the next
20. it's actually it's very generous
compared to the industry like jacob did
an incredible job
and has been great with equity so but
but early on
you're at a startup and you're like wow
i'm working really hard he's working
really hard
like why why why is the outcome going to
be so different
but honestly 18 months in and jacob
having raised the series b
and like taking a lot of the hardship
like you as a founder
are going to have to do things and be
under amount of stress
and like there there really is for the
and i don't it's probably somewhat true
for maybe those you know
those first early employees carry a
little bit of that load but the
but a founder just has to carry a
different load
and so it's always gonna fall on that
first two you know whatever people on
the cap table right
whatever it's gonna keep rolling until
it hits you at some point and
you know as it gets bigger um yeah yeah
i
you know i don't know it's an
interesting this could very easily
devolve into like the nature of
capitalism and ownership right
because it plays very much against this
like you know
constant like marxist debate about like
labor versus capital and like what are
the value and what is like
value and like because you know you like
you had this
whatever period it was one month one
year whatever that's like such
you know if you build the the greg of
your dreams which is a billion dollar
company that's touching all parts of
agriculture and plant
like how much how much of that is from
that one month right like why do you get
why do you get such an outsized return
right and not
yeah i don't know maybe it's you know
maybe that maybe that's when the
they get they'll be at my gates with
pitchforks and stuff like that
but like uh but yeah i know it is it is
it is uh
yeah i mean it's and for for
you know i think folks our listeners i
think this
is interesting because when they're
trying to make this
decision of like am i building
a b corp am i building an llc with my
friends that we're just going to share
revenues am i going to go venture
am i you know one thing i kind of went
into venture
a little blindly like i didn't
understand all of these aspects before i
filled out the yc application that was
basically like i'm doing venture i'm
gonna fill out the yc application
and luckily they kind of like
taught me like okay this is what this
means and like i'm still learning it as
i go like and now i think i kind of know
like what i'm in for
um but i think it's something
undereducated on and like
it's hard to do without first-hand
experience and like you've been in other
startups and had exits and things like
this
um which are great educational
experiences but um
it's not something to be thought on
lightly because it really will kind of
it's really hard to change paths after a
certain point right like you can go
bootstrap to venture but going back is
almost impossible
um you can even even doing something
like an llc where like you split it
between a few people while okay somebody
leaves like what do you do
you know there's not a clear path for
that these are really things like
you have to understand um when you're
when you're
taking your app into a business or
deciding what you want out of
you know your work in your life so um
it's great that you're playing with it
though like i think it's great when
when i think it's founders sometimes we
don't push the limits enough with
with just the status quo um but it's
it's how
it's how things get better like is is is
by by you know people with a little bit
of leverage being like we should do this
right exactly and i think that that's
the key is i don't think that like our
approach is
is better it's an experiment and i think
it has trade-offs
that are equal it's just what is your
desired outcome right
yeah and so what what we were really
solving for
is we wanted to end up with a team in
four or five years of people who are
very bought into still being at the
company right because we really wanted
to build
a place where like we're not trying to
graduate out into a
exit to like another giant enterprise
like i very clearly telegraphed
our vcs that our desired outcome is an
ipo
and we do have to provide an exit to our
investors um
and who knows what will happen like gosh
that's like so so pie in the sky
right hopefully we get there um but in
any case
that's the problem we were solving for
is i was thinking about like ultimately
i'd wrap this up into
working backwards where like we thought
about our end state and i wanted to have
you know 100 teammates that were like i
felt very
authentically were like just as bought
into this as i was and so i
optimized for that objective function
right
but then it comes at other trade-offs
where like david you're completely right
that like
the amount of stress that i have gone
through in the last you know year and a
half
is soul-crushing um it's like
and even i do have thoughts like well
why don't i own like
25 of the company or something right um
i definitely do not um but i'm very at
peace
which by the way that's that's that's i
mean i don't own 25 percent of the
company anymore because like
delusional stuff but like at that stage
that's that's that's pretty like
very open-handed right like you've
shared a lot and you've got other
founders obviously
or you know yeah that was the clarifying
thing that makes what i think what
you're doing
so unique is that you started with
employee zero right um
right right typically more common
practices you have some like group that
you call co-founders they get some like
chunk of the pie and then like you have
like an option
you set aside some amount of equity for
um
for employees and you work backwards
from there like we set a goal to be at a
certain percentage of employee ownership
by the end
and we worked backwards from there but i
think that's the whole point is that you
do have to start with this end state and
that's not just for equity planning
that's for all of this like what is the
end state
have an idea because you got to convince
100 other people to go there with you
you've got to like convince yourself
that you're going to want to do this
that whole time
and so you know we've we're pretty
settled on that ipo path
as well like of course it's a very far
journey and like lots can happen between
here and there and like i can't promise
i mean it is an unlikely outcome just by
the definition of it
but if but it's useful even at this
stage to be
like that's where we're going we get
there i don't know what the journey's
gonna look like but that's where we're
going so i i i think it's
a smart way to run it yeah and then what
you say earlier jacob is so true too
and i think a lot of the people
listening will fall
on a pretty wide spectrum from
just you know indie developers like i
was a few years ago
where i still had to think about this
and i actually made mistakes around this
we're like
you know oh let's build an app together
we'll do it 50 50.
no exit plan no like what if things go
wrong what if we bring in a third person
and i learned through hard knocks that
like you
you need to look at that in state and
figure out
yeah what can go wrong between here and
the end state
and and make some decisions early on
that account for those things because if
not you're going to put yourself in a
bad spot
so so anybody working on a on an
app business or any business needs to
think through these things like how do
you
split up ownership how do you manage
potential exits how do you vest
the ownership over time so that if
somebody leaves early they're not
having an outsize um return on a minimal
investment
but anyways i i really appreciate you uh
opening up about this alex and then
jacob i kind of put you on the spot
that's i um i think what you're doing
with revenue cat
is great and i mean i you know i feel
like i was you were very generous with
me
on stock and and and the first employees
we'll go ahead and link to david's
compensation package
i love the point that like it is it is
philosophical right and i think it is
worth like entrepreneurs talking about
the options
um it's fast sometimes there are
companies there's like the whole open
comp model like buffer you know actually
helping their their salaries and equity
and stuff and
uh that's an interesting approach too um
yeah
being intentional about it i think is my
advice right just don't
just don't fall into it like not not
having a point right
think about it you know not a lot
necessarily but do think about it
well and really the the working words
thing like what is what is your desired
destination can you kind of picture that
world and then
reverse engineer what steps will get you
there because that's really that's also
product development
it's company strategy financing like if
you are raising capital you have to be
able to describe
where is this capital going to get us
because it's not going to last forever
it's always going to last less long than
you think it will
right right yeah
well there is so much more i wanted to
talk to you about but
i think that what we did talk about was
really fun and interesting and honestly
really different you know we've had a
lot of podcasts that that talk about
monetization and talked about retention
or other things and so
hopefully this is a really unique take
that i think a lot of people can get
get some value from um so yeah thank you
so much
alex and uh definitely looking forward
to uh talking to you more
in the future as a as a revenue cat
customer that's uh
nice um so i'm gonna put links to your
your twitter and to the greg
app in the um uh in the show notes but
anything else
you wanted to share as we wrap up you're
hiring right so
we are hiring yeah we're hiring uh uh
senior engineers uh staff engineers
and a product designer and a head of
brand uh so if anybody wants to
apply machine learning and help machines
grow plants that we can make the
ecosystems and the food system a little
bit better
reach out to us that's a great pitch
that's really tight
and get early in a in a very unique
experiment where you're going to get
more
equity than you typically would in a
startup so that's that's a huge pitch
that's strong
it is yeah yeah okay cool we'll we'll
put links to your hiring page in the in
the show notes as well so
um but yeah thanks thanks again so much
for being on the show
yeah thanks alex it's a fun purpose i
loved it
to make sure you never miss an episode
subscribe to the show and your favorite
podcast player
thanks so much for listening until next
[Music]
time
you